I'm going to show you some cheer leading squad cheers today.
We're going to talk about chants, and I'm going to demonstrate some that you can take to your squad.
Now we're going to learn the most basic motions that you're going to need to be the basis of every cheer.
First, and foremost, we want to start out with our high "V".
We want to keep our hands in the fist.
We also want to make sure that our big dough nut holes are facing out.
So the most basic movement is going to be your high "V".
After we've learned the high "V", we can move down to a low "V", which is going to be the same thing.
One thing that is important when we're learning our "V"'s is to always make sure to keep your arms slightly in front of you to where you can see them out of the corner of your eyes.
You don't want them directly next to you.
We definitely don't want to see them behind you because that doesn't look as anesthetically pleasing to the eye.
So now that we've learned our "V"'s, we can do a few variations on them.
We can do either a right "V".
You can do a left "V".
So you can definitely use those a lot in your cheers.
The second motion to master is a "T".
A "T" is going to be similar to your "V" however your arms are going to be straight out.
Again, we want to make sure they are right out of our peripheral vision.
We don't want them to the back or to the side.
Now that we've learned a "T", another basic movement is the "goal post".
With the "goal post", it's very really important to remember not to keep your shoulders up, shrugged next to your head, but to keep them down and relaxed.
And we want to make sure that our arms are as close to touching our ears as possible.
So we want to keep our "goal post" nice and tight.
After the "goal post", we also have our "crosses", which we are going to jet out straight in front of us.
You can do a right one or a left one.
We want to cross it right in front of our body comfortably.
Next we have "K"'s.
Now with "K"'s, you can either do a right or left.
We're basically going to keep our torso forward.
We want to do a "K" motion.
You want to keep both of your arms in your peripheral vision.
You can do either a left "K" or a right "K".
Those are going to be some of the basic movements.
Last, but not least, this is a great one to get the crowd going.
We're going to learn a "punch".
It's really similar to the "goal post" that we talked about earlier.
You're going to want to keep this arm nice and flat, as close to your ear as possible.
You can go straight into your punch or you can add a little "oomph" to it at the very end.
We can do those again with our right hand or our left hand.
So now that you've learned your basic motions, we can go ahead and put them in to combinations which will then become your movements for a cheer.